(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
兎田ぺこら BIRTHDAY LIVE 新衣装お披露目
Usada Pekora BIRTHDAY LIVE New Costume Reveal
3RD GENERATION
USADA PEKORA BIRTHDAY LIVE 2023
January
兎田ぺこら BIRTHDAY LIVE 新衣装お披露目
Usada Pekora BIRTHDAY LIVE - New Outfit Reveal
スターラブレイション / 作詞：ぷらむ・長山しん / 作曲：ぷらむ
Star Love-ration / Lyrics: Plum, Shin Nagayama / Composition: Plum
Oh baby baby 今日も明日も 踏み出して Last Cinderella
Oh baby baby, today and tomorrow too, take a step forward, my Last Cinderella
不器用な愛を掲げながら ずっと駆け抜けていく 強く強く
Holding up this clumsy love, I'll keep running through it, stronger and stronger
スターラブレイション
Star Love-ration
素直になっていいんだよ 君はそう言って微笑む
"It's okay to be honest with yourself," you said with a smile
真夜中のラブストーリー 泣きそうに涙堪えてるんだ
In this midnight love story, I'm holding back tears as if I'm about to cry
分かっているんだよ 大丈夫が口癖なのは
I know that saying "I'm fine" is just a habit of yours
この先はラブストーリー それともソーリー 甘いようでスパイシー
Is there a love story ahead, or an apology? Sweet yet spicy
ドラマチックな恋も チュールドレス姿も
A dramatic romance and my tulle dress...
脱ぎ捨ててここまで全速力で 来たんだよ
I've cast them all off and come this far at full speed
Oh baby baby 今日も明日も 踏み出して Last Cinderella
Oh baby baby, today and tomorrow too, take a step forward, my Last Cinderella
泣き笑いながら見る空は 最高に美しいんだ
The sky I see while laughing and crying is the most beautiful thing
Oh baby baby 胸の中の 想いを高く舞い上がれ
Oh baby baby, let the feelings in my heart soar high
不器用な愛を掲げながら ずっと駆け抜けていく 強く強く
Holding up this clumsy love, I'll keep running through it, stronger and stronger
スターラブレイション
Star Love-ration
誤解される性格だから また心が疲れるんだね
Because of my misunderstood personality, my heart gets tired again
この先もそうやって 強がり言っておなじように生きていくの？
Will you keep putting on a brave face and living like that from now on?
星降るこの夜に 何かが揺れ始めた
On this starry night, something began to sway
描いた理想の自分になるため 走り出す
I'll start running to become the ideal self I envisioned
Oh baby baby 今日も明日も 踏み出して Last Cinderella
Oh baby baby, today and tomorrow too, take a step forward, my Last Cinderella
鏡の前に立つ私は 最高に美しいんだ
Standing before the mirror, I am at my most beautiful
Oh baby baby 胸の中の 迷う心よ舞い散らして
Oh baby baby, let the indecisive heart in my chest scatter away
弱さ越えていくこの笑顔は 光る風の中の太陽なんだ
This smile that overcomes weakness is the sun within the shining wind
スターラブレイション
Star Love-ration
La la la...
雲ひとつない空に 両手いっぱいの愛が
In a cloudless sky, with both hands full of love
まっすぐに君へ届けに行くよ どこまでも
I'll go to deliver it straight to you, no matter how far
Oh baby baby 今日も明日も 踏み出して Last Cinderella
Oh baby baby, today and tomorrow too, take a step forward, my Last Cinderella
泣き笑いながら見る空は 最高に美しいんだ
The sky I see while laughing and crying is the most beautiful thing
Oh baby baby 胸の中の 想いを高く舞い上がれ
Oh baby baby, let the feelings in my heart soar high
不器用な愛を掲げながら ずっと駆け抜けていく 強く強く
Holding up this clumsy love, I'll keep running through it, stronger and stronger
スターラブレイション
Star Love-ration
Yeah!
可愛くてごめん
I'm Sorry for Being So Cute
私が私のこと愛して何が悪いの？
What's wrong with me loving myself?
嫉妬でしょうか？
Is it jealousy?
痛いだとか変わってるとか
Saying it's painful or weird,
届きませんね、そのリプライ
those replies don't reach me.
大好きな お洋服
My favorite clothes,
大好きな お化粧で
my favorite makeup.
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
The usual half-twins, curled,
お出かけしよ
let's go out.
日傘持って ぼっちだって
Bringing a parasol, even if I'm alone,
幸せだもん！
I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん 生まれてきちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん 気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
Chu! Sorry for being manipulative, you're curious, right? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん 努力しちゃっててごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for working so hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん 女子力高くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious, sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね？ ざまあ
You're getting annoyed, right? Serves you right.
あなたはあなたのことだけどうぞ
You please just mind your own business,
私に干渉しないでください
please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね、その陰口
but those backbitings don't reach me.
重い厚底ブーツ
Heavy platform boots,
お気に入りのリュックで
with my favorite backpack.
崩せない前髪 くしでといて
My unshakeable bangs, combed through,
お出かけしよ
let's go out.
軽い女？ ふざけんな
An easy girl? Don't mess with me,
重すぎるっつーの！
I'm way too heavy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん この時代生きてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for living in this era.
Chu! 目立っててごめん 意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out, you can't help but notice me, right? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん 自分磨きしてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for improving myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん 虜にしちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for playing the coquette, sorry for making you captivated.
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ ざまあ
You're annoyed, right? Serves you right.
趣味の違い 変わり者と
Differences in hobbies, even if
馬鹿にされても
mocked as an eccentric,
負けたくない 怖くもない
I don't want to lose, I'm not afraid
あんたらのこと
of people like you.
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own ally,
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to value myself the most.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I don't want to make myself endure unreasonable things,
それが私
that is me.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん 生まれてきちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being manipulative,
人生楽しんでごめん
sorry for enjoying life.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん 努力しちゃっててごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute, sorry for working so hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん 女子力高くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious, sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね？ ざまあ
You're getting annoyed, right? Serves you right.
はい、みんなー！
Hi, everyone!
1曲目は「スターラプレーション」、そして2曲目は「可愛くてごめん」ぺこでしたー！
The first song was 'Star-Revelation', and the second was 'Kawaikute Gomen'-peko!
どうぺこか？ どうぺこか？
How was it? How was it?
この後はみんなお待ちかねのコラボパートいくぺこ！
After this, it's time for the long-awaited collaboration part-peko!
久しぶりの人や初めて歌う人、お馴染みの人もいるぺこだし...
There are people I haven't seen in a while, people I'm singing with for the first time, and familiar faces too-peko...
後半にはついにあれが...！
In the latter half, finally that will...!
てなわけでぺこちゃん準備してくる！ じゃあねー！
So Peko-chan is going to go get ready! See ya!
行くよ！
Here we go!
まみむめも モヤモヤだ 君も Are you ready? 準備はいい？
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo, you're feeling hazy too, Are you ready? Are you prepared?
スキップ＆ステップ 1, 2, 3, はい！ ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム
Skip & Step 1, 2, 3, yes! Positive Star Dance Time
夢色奏でるよ空に Shall we dance?
I'll play dream colors in the sky, shall we dance?
明日（あす）に笑われるくらい
Enough for tomorrow to laugh at us
しかめ面お月様も一緒に Shall we dance?
Even the frowning moon, let's dance together, shall we?
最高の気分ね
It's the best feeling
ワンツースリーのリズムで
With a one-two-three rhythm
ワンツースリー魔法をかけて
Cast a one-two-three spell
君だけのステップだから
Because it's your own step
世界がほら輝くのさ
Look, the world starts to shine
Wake up Wake up 遅れないでよね
Wake up, Wake up, don't be late
魅惑のダンスタイム
A charming dance time
Jumpin' Jumpin' 恥ずかしがらずに
Jumpin', Jumpin', don't be shy
ハイハイハイハイ！
Hi hi hi hi!
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
ぱぴぷぺポジティブダンスタイム
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
嫌なことも Let's dance
Let's dance away the bad things
君と一緒に踊れば
If I dance with you
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
今はぎこちないリズムでも
Even if the rhythm is awkward now
青空に Let's be ambitious
To the big sky, let's be ambitious
きっと輝いてくから
I'm sure it will start to shine
ノリのりのりの君も Are you ready?
You there, feeling the groove, are you ready?
準備はいい？
Are you ready?
スキップだって 1, 2, 3 ハイ！
Even skipping, 1, 2, 3, go!
ポジティブダンスタイム
Positive Dance Time
雲色奏でるよ空に Shall we dance?
I'll play cloud colors in the sky, shall we dance?
昨日笑い飛ばすくらい
Enough to laugh off yesterday
泣き虫お星様も一緒に Shall we dance?
Even the crybaby stars, let's dance together, shall we?
笑顔にしちゃおう
Let's turn it into a smile
ワンツースリーのリズムで
With a one-two-three rhythm
ワンツースリー魔法をかけて
Cast a one-two-three spell
君だけのステップだから
Because it's your own step
世界がほら輝いた
Look, the world started to shine
Wake up Wake up 止まらないでよね
Wake up, Wake up, don't stop
素敵なダンスタイム
A wonderful dance time
Jumpin' Jumpin' 無我夢中でほら
Jumpin', Jumpin', losing ourselves, look
ハイハイハイイェーイ！
Hi hi hi yay!
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
ぱぴぷぺポジティブダンスタイム
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
迷いも全部 Let's dance
Let's dance away all our doubts
君と一緒に奏でよう
Let's play together with you
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
今は慣れないメロディでも
Even if it's an unfamiliar melody now
夢色に Let's be ambitious
To the dream colors, let's be ambitious
きっと届くから
I'm sure it will reach you
Wake up Wake up 遅れないでよね
Wake up, Wake up, don't be late
最高のダンスタイム
The best dance time
Jumpin' Jumpin' 思いのままに
Jumpin', Jumpin', just as you please
ほらハイハイハイハイ！
Look, hi hi hi hi!
だから素晴らしいの
That's why it's wonderful
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
ぱぴぷぺポジティブダンスタイム
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
涙を拭いて Let's dance
Wipe your tears and let's dance
君と一緒に踊れば
If I dance with you
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
今は真っ白なキャンバスも
Even if the canvas is blank now
君色に Let's be ambitious
To your own color, let's be ambitious
描けるの
You can draw it
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
もう一回！
One more time!
ポジティブダンスタイム
Positive Dance Time
出し出し出したい
I want to let it out, let it out, let it out
ぱぴぷぺポジティブダンスタイム
Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
みんなでさぁ Let's dance
Everyone, come on, let's dance
楽しい楽しい優勝だね
Fun, fun, it's a victory
虹色の毎日を
A rainbow-colored everyday
ずっとずっと笑い疲れるくらい
Forever and ever, until we're tired of laughing
踊ってたい Let's be ambitious
I want to keep dancing, let's be ambitious
でも今日はおやすみ
But for today, good night
準備はいい？
Are you ready?
ワンツースリー ハイ！
One-two-three, go!
ポジティブダンスタイム
Positive Dance Time
チューリングラブ
Turing Love
作詞：ナユタン星人(ナユタナアルカ)
Lyrics: Nayutalien (Nayutana Alka)
作曲：ナユタン星人
Composition: Nayutalien
あ、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まず計測機がわからない
First, I don't know the measuring device
要は恋してる時が恋らしい
In short, being in love is what love's like
わずか 1, 2, 3
Just 1, 2, 3
あ、愛の方程式解けない
Ah, I can't solve the equation of love
まず普通の計算も解けない
First off, I can't even do normal math
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that state itself is lovely
I know, you know
もう大抵の事象において Q を置いて A を出して解けるのに
I can solve it by putting Q and getting A in most cases, but...
勘違って間違って 解のないこの気持ちは ララララ
Misunderstanding, making mistakes, this feelings with no answer, la la la la
検証 is 明瞭
Verification is clear
感情論は相対性
Emotional theories are relativity
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, a mellow that can't be solved even if we stare at each other
ワッツイズラブ？ 今は 1, 2, 3 で証拠を出そうか
What is love? Let's show the evidence now with 1, 2, 3
言葉で生み出す結晶 鼓動でたどるアンサー
Crystals created by words, the answer traced by heartbeats
測ったって不確定性 僕らの BPM
Even if measured, it's uncertainty, our BPM
チューリングラブ 証明待ったなし信じなきゃノー
Turing Love, no waiting for proof, if you don't believe, it's a no
ピタゴラス
Pythagoras
確信させてリーマン
Let me be sure, Riemann
予測不能な階乗
Unpredictable factorial
いま触れてみる
I'll try touching it now
さあ証明しよう
Now let's prove it
間違いのないように
So there are no mistakes
証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情 全部 全部
This feeling, all of it, all of it
証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるのなら
If there is a correct answer
証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルな Q.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明した
Today I proved it
目に見えない
Invisible
無理難題
Unreasonable challenge
A-S-A-P
導き出したい
Want to derive
最適解
The optimal solution
何度空回ったって
No matter how many times I spun my wheels
ぶつかっちゃったって
Or crashed
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です
Even the process of unraveling this mysterious anomaly is a necessary condition
答を請うに丁度ええ塩梅の距離を保てよ
Keep just the right distance to ask for the answer
的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was something like that
意外もこうして見当たらんないし
But I can't find the unexpected either
公式集にも載ってないから
It's not in the formula book either
君と生み出してみたいじゃんって
I want to try creating it with you
三次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in the three-dimensional (world)
バグったって
Even if it bugs out
割りとってゴールで
It's pretty much a goal
近くなって
Getting closer
遠くなって
Getting further away
揺れるこの気持ちの針も
The needle of these swaying feelings, too
同条件だよ
Are under the same conditions
ステッピン モーションは
The stepping motion is
相愛性
Love-reciprocity
ステイク
Stake
チューリングラブ
Turing Love
騒ぎ出した胸の痛くなるほど
So much that it makes my chest ache
証明は 今も数式を数えるようだ
The proof still feels like counting formulas
曖昧も除外して
Excluding all ambiguity
最大の 6825 を
The maximum 6825
いま二人なら 実証できそう
The two of us could demonstrate it now
チューリングラブ
Turing Love
見つめあったって解けないメロウ
A mellow that won't be solved even if we stare at each other
ワン バイ ワン いまは二人で明かそうか
One by one, let's reveal it together now
言葉で生み出してみたいじゃん
I want to try creating it with words
解るまで あと少し
Just a little more until we understand
測ったって不可確定
Uncertain even if measured
ぜんぶ僕らのディペンデンシー
It's all our dependency
チューリングラブ
Turing Love
宙に舞ったってそうな笑顔も
That smile that seems to dance in the air
ワン バイ ワン いまは XYZ までわかりそう
One by one, now it seems we'll understand up to XYZ
確信させてピタゴラス
Let me be sure, Pythagoras
確信させてリーマン
Let me be sure, Riemann
予測済み階乗
Already predicted factorial
いま触れてみる
I'll try touching it now
さあ証明しよう
Now let's prove it
間違いのないように
So there are no mistakes
証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情 全部 全部
This feeling, all of it, all of it
証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるのなら
If there is a correct answer
証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルな Q.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！
I love you! I love you! I love you! ...
この気持ち 止まりませ〜ん！！！！
This feeling won't stop!!!!
すきっ！
Suki!
君と幼なじみで生まれたい
I want to be born as your childhood friend
徒歩2分に住んでてほしい
I want you to live 2 minutes away on foot
そして大人になって突然再会してみたり
And then meet again suddenly as adults
...ってね！
...just kidding!
もしくは第一印象 最悪な初対面だったり
Or maybe a first meeting with the worst first impression
ボーイズ・ミーツ・ガール
Boy meets girl
ごちゃまぜシチュエーション
A jumbled situation
実は君が悪の組織と戦うヒーロー
Actually, you're a hero fighting an evil organization
という秘密があったり
Having a secret like that
なんだかんだ 独り占めしたいな
Somehow or other, I want to keep you all to myself
ああ 君に出会った日から
Ah, since the day I met you
私の毎日はラブコメに変わったんだ
My every day has turned into a rom-com
すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！
I love you! I love you! I love you! ...
君が君であるための存在
Everything that makes you who you are
すべてが
All of it
弾けそうなんだ もうダメだ
Is about to burst, it's no good
抑えきれません
I can't hold it back
いつか
Someday
結ばれますように
I hope that we'll be together
すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！すき！
I love you! I love you! I love you! ...
そんな
Like that
予告なしに訪れるんだ
It visits without warning
髪をほどいた私見て
Look at me with my hair let down
君が
That you
キュンと キュンと
Feel a heart-throb, a heart-throb
しますように
I hope you do
ひと目見たとき ビビビッときた
When I first saw you, I felt a spark
身体に電気が走った
An electric shock ran through my body
ぜったい ぜったい ぜったい これは運命だ
Definitely, definitely, definitely, this is destiny
ねぇ ほら
Hey, look
ドキドキしてやばいの
My heart's racing, it's crazy
世界中で君だけだよ 叫んじゃいたいぜ
You're the only one in the world, I want to shout it out
すき!
I love you!
すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you!
すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you!
君を振り向かせるには どうしたらいいんだろう
What should I do to make you look my way?
やっぱり もっと自分を変えなきゃいけないのかな
I wonder if I really have to change myself more
とか思ったりしたけどさ
I thought about that, but
私は私のまま君に伝えればいいんだよね
I should just tell you as I am, right?
ああ 誰でも主人公なんだ
Ah, everyone is the protagonist
他の誰でもない私を生きてゆくんだ
I'll live my life as no one else but me
すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you!
君が君であるための存在 すべてが
Everything that exists for you to be who you are
弾けそうなんだ もうだめだ 抑えきれない
I'm about to burst, it's no use, I can't hold it back
いつか結ばれますように
I hope we'll be together someday
あーーー!
Ahhh!
すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you!
君がくれたたくさんの気持ちのすべてが
Every single one of the many feelings you gave me
こぼれそうなんだ もうだめだ この想いが
Is about to overflow, it's no use, these feelings
ぎゅぎゅっと 伝わりますように
I hope they reach you with a tight squeeze
すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you! I love you!
全速力の向こうに
Beyond full speed
何かがきっと 待ってる
Something is surely waiting
曲がり角で 君に会えますように
I hope I can meet you at the street corner
すき!すき!すき!
I love you! I love you! I love you!
何もかもが
Everything is
あああーーー!
Aaaahhh!
好きです!
I love you!
サラバ、愛しき悲しみたちよ
Farewell, my dear sorrows
行くの? 行かないの?
Going? Not going?
有象無象じゃ言えよ 言いたいよ
Say it, if you're the rabble, I want to say it
VS 嫌じゃない 裏か表か
VS, I don't hate it, is it heads or tails?
底なしのクエスチョン
A bottomless question
だけどどうしてどうにもこうにもタイト
But why is it so tight anyway?
あはっ　ディンギリンギ
Ah ha, dingy-ringy
見猿 言わざる 聞かざるでござる
See no evil, speak no evil, hear no evil
表裏あやうき 道近からずです
The path of dual nature is precarious and far
お見逸れされたらやめたくなります
If you overlook me, I'll want to stop
うたったらゆるすたてられたらわらえ
If I sing, forgive me; if I'm put up, laugh
こころの声がこだまする
The voice of the heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
なまいきなくらいの夜明けに
To a dawn that's almost cheeky
行かないで
Don't go
泣かないで
Don't cry
サラバ、昨日を脱ぎ捨てて
Farewell, shedding off yesterday
勇気の声をふりしぼれ
Wring out a voice of courage
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
To know the love named "self"
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep
迷えるこころの叫びを
The cry of a straying heart
振り返るな 我らの世界は
Don't look back, our world is
まだ始まったばかり
only just beginning
...始まったばかりだ
...It's only just begun.
寂しい想いさせてんじゃねえよ
Don't make me feel lonely.
やるの? さばくの? そばにいればいいじゃん
Will you do it? Will you judge? Just stay by my side.
ソワソワしちゃって まさかの号泣
Getting all restless, unexpectedly wailing.
褒めて まさかの全力で
Praise me, unexpectedly with all your might.
そしてどこまでも
And to wherever...
続く夢を見た
...I saw a continuing dream.
天使が舞い降りてきた
An angel came dancing down.
そしてどこまでも
And to wherever...
続く空の元で
...under the continuing sky,
自由になりたい
I want to be free.
1, 2 and 3, 4, 5
Get Up, Stand Up, Free Your Soul
Stand Up and Make Some Noise
Oh-ho, Do it! Do it!
Oh-ho, Do it now
心の声が木霊する
The voice of the heart echoes.
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope.
生意気なくらいの夜明けに
At a dawn that's almost cheeky,
揺らすんだ
Shake it,
Shake it.
進むんだ
Move forward,
Move forward.
サラバ、昨日を脱ぎ捨てて
Farewell, cast off yesterday.
勇気の声を振り絞れ
Wring out your voice of courage.
「じぶん」という名の愛を知るために
In order to know the love named "myself."
眠れない羊の群れよ
Oh, flock of sleepless sheep,
迷える心の叫びを
the cry of a wandering heart.
振り返るな 我らの世界はまだ
Don't look back, our world has still...
始まったばかりだ
...only just begun.
Oh-ho, Do it! Do it!
Oh-ho, Do it now
Do it now
哀れみをください
Please, have pity on me.
落ちた小鳥にそっと触れるような
As if gently touching a fallen little bird,
悲しみをください
please, give me sadness.
涙ぐんで 見下ろして
Tearfully looking down,
「かわいそう」だと口に出して
say it aloud, "how pitiful."
靴の先で転がしても構わないわ
I don't mind if you roll me around with the tip of your shoe.
汚れててもいいからと
Saying it's okay if I'm dirty,
泥だらけの手を取って
take my mud-covered hands.
ねえ 輪になって踊りましょう
Hey, let's dance in a circle.
目障りな有象無象は全て
All the eyesore rabble,
食べてしまいましょう
let's eat them all up.
スパイスは堪え難いくらいがいいわ
The spice is best when it's almost unbearable.
怯えた小鳥は
The frightened little bird
「さよなら」なんて言えなくて
couldn't even say "goodbye,"
愛を乞う仕草で 黙り込んで
falling silent in a gesture of begging for love.
慎まし つもりでいた
I intended to be modest.
散々傷ついて 優しい世界に
Severely hurt, to a gentle world,
誰だって行きたいわ
anyone would want to go.
ひとつに溶けてしまいましょう
Let's melt into one.
憎しみも
Hatred, too
愛情も
And affection
むしゃむしゃと
I'll gobble them all up
頬張ってしまいましょう
Let's feast on them
混沌の
Inside this chaotic
甘い甘い
Sweet, sweet
壺の中で
Jar of ours
あいまいにはしたくないから
I don't want things to be vague
会いたいと思うのよ
So I want to see you
I know you, hit step with me
愛されていたいだけ
I just want to be loved
Lie, Lie, Lie, you'll be with me
雷鳴のさくところ
Where the thunder roars
惨憺たるヘブンリー・フィーリング
A wretched heavenly feeling
愛だけ残ればいい
If only love would remain
しんしんと悲しみだけが
Silently, only sadness
降り積もる
Continues to pile up
願わくばもう一度だけ
If I could, just once more
見つめ草
I'd gaze at you
絆結んだ
We tied a bond
遠い春の陽を
In the distant spring sun
傷跡さえも
Even the scars
消えてしまうの
Will disappear
やがてキラキラ夢の中
Soon, within a sparkling dream
朽ちていく
They will decay
光はあなたに
The light should surely
届くはずだから
Reach you
まぶしくて涙が止まらない
It's so bright, I can't stop crying
ねえどうか側にいて
Hey, please stay by my side
泥だらけの手を取って
Take my mud-covered hand
離さないで
And don't let go
どうかずっと側にいて
Please stay by my side forever
離さないで
Don't let go
暗くなるの側にいて
It's getting dark, stay by my side
離さないで 見えないわ
Don't let go, I can't see
ただずっと側にいて
Just stay by my side always
離さないで
Don't let go
ただずっと愛してる
I will always love you
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い
Make sure you handle me
心得て
Exactly like that, okay?
その一、いつもと違う髪型に気がつくこと
Number one: noticed my hair is different than usual
その二、ちゃんと靴まで見ること
Number two: look properly all the way down to my shoes
いいね？
Got it?
その三、わたしの一言には
Number three: for every word I say
三つの言葉で返事すること
Reply with three words
わかったら
If you understand
右手が空いてるのをなんとかして！
Do something about my empty right hand!
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
キミに心から思って欲しいの
I want you to feel from the bottom of your heart
かわいいって
That I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
気がついて ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか
Now for some reason
あまいものが食べたい！
I want to eat something sweet!
いますぐに、よ！
Right now!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Faults? You mean "being cute", right?
文句は許しませんの
I won't allow any complaints
あのね、わたしの話
Hey, are you listening
ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと…
To what I'm saying? Wait...
あ、それ
Ah, that...
…とね
...and you know,
白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ
A white horse is a given, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
わかったら かしずいて 手を取って 「お姫様」って
If you understand, bow down, take my hand, and call me "Princess."
べつに わがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね 少しぐらい 叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little.
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My one and only prince in the world.
気がついて ほらほら おててが空いてます
Notice me! Look, look, my hand is empty.
無口で不愛想な王子さま
My quiet and unsociable prince.
もう、どうして！
Geez, why?!
気が付いてよ早く
Notice me already!
あっ！
Ah!
ぜったい君は分かってない
You definitely don't understand.
分かってないわ…
You just don't get it...
いちごの載ったショートケーキ
Shortcake topped with strawberries.
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with special eggs.
みんな みんな 我慢します…
I'll hold back on all of them...
わがままな子だと思わないで
So don't think I'm a selfish girl.
私だってやればできるの
I can do it if I try.
あとで後悔するわよ
You'll regret it later!
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I am
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Keep your eyes on me, or I might go somewhere else.
ふいに抱きしめられた 急にそんな、えっ？
Suddenly you hugged me. So out of the blue, huh?
「惹かれる、危ないよ」
"You're so attractive, it's dangerous."
そう言ってそっぽ向く君
You said that and looked away.
こっちのが危ないわよ
You're the dangerous one here!
そして君が知らずに 幸せな灰になったとて
Even if you turn into happy ashes without knowing,
僕は今更 君が好きだって
I'm only now realizing that I love you.
地球最後の告白を
The Earth's Last Confession
大人になりたくないよなんて 大人ぶってさ
Saying things like "I don't want to grow up" while acting like an adult,
駆け出した少年の日
In those days when I was a boy running wild.
どーやら僕に訪れた悪戯は
It seems the prank that befell me
相当タチの悪い 不老不死の世界
Was a rather malicious world of immortality.
「神様ステキなプレゼントありがと」なんて
Saying things like "Thank you God for this wonderful gift,"
到底的外れな 幼い冗談のふりに
Pretending to make a completely misplaced, childish joke.
大事に隠した 片思いは察してくれないんだ
You didn't notice the unrequited love I carefully hid.
追い越してく 戻れない憧憬
Memories of longing that I can't return to overtake me.
好きな人に さよならを
Saying goodbye to the one I love.
いつか見た夕焼けは あんなにキレイだったのに
The sunset I saw back then was so beautiful,
恋なんて呼ぶには 穢れすぎてしまったよ
But it's become too tainted to be called love.
そして君が知らずに 幸せな灰になったとて
Even if you turn into happy ashes without knowing,
僕は今更 君が好きだって
I'm only now realizing that I love you.
気付いたよ
I finally realized it.
100年前の同じ日に 君のおばあちゃんは
One hundred years ago on this same day, your grandmother
同じことを言ったんだ
Said the exact same thing.
君の孫のひ孫のその最期に
At the end of your grandchild's great-grandchild's life,
僕はまた一人になる
I will be alone once again.
移ろうメトロポリスと 君の誇りな花束を
The changing metropolis and your proud bouquet of flowers.
恋なんて呼ぶには 穢れすぎてしまったね
To call it love, it's become far too defiled.
そして 時間が流れて 世界が灰になったとて
And as time passes, even if the world turns to ash,
僕は今でも 不意に君を思い出すんだ
Even now, I suddenly find myself remembering you.
誰もいない 枯れた世界で
In a withered world where no one else remains,
悪戯の意味を知ったよ
I learned the meaning of a prank.
臆病でも 今なら言えるんだ
Even if I'm a coward, I can say it now.
地球最後 この告白を
This confession at the end of the Earth.
いつか見た夕焼けは あんなに綺麗だったのに
The sunset I once saw was so beautiful, and yet...
恋なんて呼ぶには 遠回りしすぎたよ
To call it love, I've taken too long a detour.
そして 何もかもが 手遅れの灰になったとて
And even if everything has turned into too-late ashes,
僕は今さら 君が好きだって
Even at this late hour, that I love you...
君が好きだったと言え...
That I loved you, I can't even say...
シュガーソングとビターステップ
作詞・作曲 田淵智也
Sugar Song to Bitter Step
Lyrics & Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to the uproar like a massive cataclysm,
こんな日常を平和と見間違える
I mistake such a daily life for peace.
rambling coaster 揺さぶられながら
While being shaken by a rambling coaster,
見失えないものは何だ
What is it that I cannot lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed up by the concept of equality fundamentalism,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
Even my heart is like just another "et cetera."
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
Hate it, love it, if I don't speak properly,
人形とさして変わらないし
I'm not much different from a doll.
ああ 宵街を行く人だかりは
Ah, the crowds walking through the evening streets,
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
They look happy, or they look lonely.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
Contrast flies around the musical staff,
歌とリズムになる
Becoming song and rhythm.
ママレード＆シュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet and bitter, making my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's keep the party going toward the south-southwest,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, becoming a chain and reflecting.
蓋然性合理主義の正体にもまれて
Buffeted by the true nature of probability rationalism,
僕らの音楽は道具に成り下がる？
Will our music degenerate into a mere tool?
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Look at me, don't turn your back on me,
それは正論にならないけど
Though that doesn't make for a sound argument.
祭囃子のそのあとで
After the festival music has ended,
高ぶったままの人 泣き出してしまう人
Some remain excited, others start to cry.
多分同じだろう でも言葉にしようものなら
It's probably the same, but if I try to put it into words,
稚拙が極まれり
It would be the height of clumsiness.
最高だってシュガーソング 幸せってビターステップ
The best sugar song, happiness bitter step,
死ねない理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reasons for not dying right there.
惜しがったって等速度で明日は来ちゃうけど
Even if we regret it, tomorrow will arrive at a constant speed,
脳内天気予報のアップデートは果たしたなら
But if you've finished updating the weather forecast in your mind...
Someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if the frenzy dies down
Someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if logic loses its meaning
Feeling unsung 鳴らし続けることだけが
Feeling unsung, only the continuous sound...
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる、QED!
...becomes the proof that makes us who we are, QED!
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
生きてく理由をそこに映し出せ
Reflect the reason for living right there
北北東は後方へ、その距離が誇らしい
North-Northeast to the rear, that distance is something to be proud of
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep surprising the whole world
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & Sugar Song, Peanuts & Bitter Step
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet and bitter, it's making my head spin
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head South-Southwest and let's keep the party going
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる I feel 上々
It'll be a night that surprises the whole world, I feel great
連鎖になってリフレクション Goes On
Becoming a chain, the reflection goes on
一去去って 一指しなって待って一教
Leaving all at once, becoming one finger, waiting for the best
Wow Wow...
一去去って 一指しなって待って一教
Leaving all at once, becoming one finger, waiting for the best
You got happiness, feel some melodies
はぁ〜！ぺこら〜！
Haa! Pekora!
ぺこらちゃん！
Pekora-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがと〜！
Thank you!
え、すご！新衣装じゃん！
Wow, amazing! It's a new outfit!
かわいい！
Cute!
じっくり見せてぺこよ
Let us see it closely, peko.
じっくり見せてご覧なさいよ
Let us have a good look.
足元まで見せてよ
Show us all the way down to your feet.
お姫様だったんだね
You really were a princess.
ティアラもかぶっちゃって
Even wearing a tiara.
かわいい〜！
So cute!
うさぎに真珠だ
Pearls for a rabbit.
おい！ちょっと何見てんのよ！
Hey! What are you looking at!
もったいないわね
What a waste.
どういうことだよおい！
What do you mean by that, hey!
拉致して連れて帰ろうかな
I might just kidnap her and take her home.
やめろやめろ
Stop it, stop it.
髪型も可愛いね
Your hairstyle is cute too.
編み込みみたいになってる
It's like a braid.
お花持ってる
She's holding a flower.
人参のお花？
A carrot flower?
これ食べれそうぺこだけど
This looks edible, peko.
食べないでね
Don't eat it.
みんな食べない？
Does anyone want a bite?
やめろやめろ
Stop it, stop it.
うさぎ食べたい！
I want to eat the rabbit!
みんな来てくれてありがと
Thank you everyone for coming.
いきなり締めようとしてる
Trying to wrap it up already.
早すぎるでしょ
That's way too early.
まだだよまだ
Not yet, not yet.
え、もうそんな時間？
Oh, is it that time already?
実はもうちょっと残ってるので
Actually, there's a little bit more left.
いろいろあるので
Since there's various things.
またみんなで遊ぼうや
Let's play together again later.
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
え、ゲストなのに？
Eh, even though we're guests?
居座りたい！
I want to stay!
時間ギリギリまでいようとするんじゃないよ
Don't try to stay until the very last second.
一緒にいたいよ〜
We want to be with you~
帰りたくないよ〜
I don't want to go home~
ぺこら〜
Pekora~
みんな頑張ってね
Good luck everyone.
ありがとぺこ！
Thank you peko!
ちょっと自由すぎるぺこ
They're a bit too free-spirited, peko.
この後も歌とお知らせもあるので
After this, there will be more songs and announcements.
お楽しみに！バイバイ！
Look forward to it! Bye-bye!
Synchrogazer
作詞 水樹奈々 作詞・作曲 上松範康(Elements Garden)
Lyrics by Nana Mizuki, Lyrics & Composition by Noriyasu Agematsu (Elements Garden)
Listen to my song... Oh...
僕の声は聞こえていますか？ Please tell me
Can you hear my voice? Please tell me
答えのない虚構の空目指し Far away
Aiming for a fictional sky with no answers, far away
言葉じゃ足りないから 僕のすべて受け止めて
Because words aren't enough, take in everything of me
制御できない、したくないよ
I can't control it, and I don't want to
初めて知る感覚
A feeling I'm learning for the first time
君に歌うよ
I'll sing to you
永遠の始まりを
The beginning of eternity
だから笑って 誰よりも熱く
So smile, hotter than anyone else
誰よりも強く抱きしめるよ
I'll hold you tighter than anyone else
震える心 揺さぶればいい
If my heart trembles, let it shake
何かが動き出す
Something starts to move
僕ら...
We...
きっと生まれた日から
must have been looking for
出会えるポーズを ずっと探してたんだ
the pose to meet ever since the day we were born
風の鳴く夜は思い出して
On nights when the wind cries, remember
共に...
and together...
奏でた奇跡...
...we played a miracle...
天に舞うよ
...that dances in the sky
僕らの思いは届いていますか？
Are our feelings reaching you?
True or Bye
胸を打つ度 もどかしさが募る
Every time my heart beats, frustration grows
Fly or Bye
いつも避けてばかりだ
I'm always just avoiding things,
明日を見失いそうで
as if I'm about to lose sight of tomorrow
傷つけないように
So as not to hurt anyone,
傷つかないように
so as not to get hurt...
嘘だけが増えていく
...only lies keep increasing
適当に笑っていたいくらいに
So much that I want to just laugh it off,
苦しいほどに そう愛おしいから
it's so painful because it's so dear
求める気持ち 抑えきれない
I was afraid of myself, unable to suppress
自分が怖かった
my desires
やっと 体中巡る
At last, I've noticed the rhythm of instinct
本能のリズムに 気付いたんだ
coursing through my body
もう二度と君を離さないよ
I'll never let you go again
いつもの昨日より...
More than the usual yesterday...
未来を照らす
...I'll light up the future
この身 朽ち果てても
Even if this body decays completely
伝えたいものがある
there's something I want to convey
響け 命の歌
Resonate, song of life
彼方 羽ばたいて
Flapping wings to the distance
だから笑って
So smile,
誰よりも熱く 誰よりも強く 抱きしめたい
I want to embrace you hotter than anyone, stronger than anyone
震える心 揺さぶればいい
It's okay to shake your trembling heart
何かが動き出す
Something starts to move
僕ら...
We...
きっと生まれた日から
must have been looking for
出会えるポーズを ずっと探してたんだ
the pose to meet ever since the day we were born
風の鳴く夜は思い出して
On nights when the wind cries, remember
共に...
and together...
紡ぎ出した奇跡...
...the miracle we spun out...
天を描くよ
...will draw the heavens
みんな、みんなー！
Everyone, everyone!
どうぺこだった？可愛かった？
How was it-peko? Was I cute?
そんな君にお知らせだ！それはこちら！ドゥルン！
I have an announcement for you! It's this! *Drumroll*
兎田ぺこら誕生日記念2023のグッズ発売！
Usada Pekora Birthday Celebration 2023
イエイイエイイエイ！
goods are now on sale! Yay yay yay!
ということで商品は、こちら！
And so, here are the products!
ドゥルン、こっちだった。あははは。
*Drumroll*, it was this way. Hahaha.
はぐれ先生の描き下ろしの等身大タペストリーと、
A life-sized tapestry illustrated by Hagure-sensei, and
今年は、何年ぺこですか？
What year is it this year-peko?
さぁ、卯年！ということで、
That's right, the Year of the Rabbit! And so,
絵馬とお守り！
an ema and an amulet!
しかもこのお守りは、超幸運お守りぺこだから、
And this amulet is a Super Good Luck Amulet-peko,
これを持ってたら確実…いや、個人差ありますぺこですけども、
so if you have this, you'll definitely... well, there are individual differences-peko,
きっと運がいい間違いなし！
but you'll surely have good luck!
そして野うさぎのティッシュカバー！
And the Nousagi tissue cover!
こちらが、えーぺこちゃんの誕生日記念グッズとなっております。
These are Peko-chan's birthday celebration goods.
どうぺこですか？可愛くないぺこですか？
How are they-peko? Aren't they cute-peko?
等身大タペストリーと絵馬はね、はぐれママの描き下ろしなので是非是非！
The life-sized tapestry and ema are illustrated by Hagure-mama, so definitely get them!
そして、ぺこらの一押しはやっぱ、幸運お守りかなーって思っております。
And, Pekora's top recommendation is the good luck amulet.
みんながね、卯年をね、あのー幸せに暮らせるように、
I hope everyone can live happily during the Year of the Rabbit,
このお守りをね、いつも肌身離さず持っていたら、
so if you keep this amulet with you at all times,
きっといいことが絶対に起きるぺこだから、是非要チェック！
something good will definitely happen-peko, so please check it out!
あとティッシュカバーもね、あの寒い時期とかに鼻かんでよろぺこです！
Also, the tissue cover too, please use it to blow your nose during the cold season!
そしてこちらね、あのフルセットで買っていただいた方には、
And for those who buy the full set,
兎田ぺこら箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカード！
you'll get a postcard with Usada Pekora's foil-stamped signature and message!
ポストカードがついてくるので
...so it comes with a postcard,
ぜひぜひみなさんよろしくお願いします！
so please check it out, everyone!
そしたら、ま、この後ね
And then, well, after this,
わかってる人はいると思うんだけど
I'm sure some of you already know,
メンバー限定でアンコールライブもあるぺこなのので
there's also an encore live for members only, Peko,
ぜひお忘れなくよろぺこです！
so please don't forget it, Yoropeko!
てなわけで今日もねみんな本当にいつもありがとう！
Anyway, thank you all so much for today, as always!
てなわけで
And with that...
おつぺこでしたー！
Otsupeko-deshita!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!